<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Everything Engineering</title>
    <link>https://abhay.rs/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Everything Engineering</description>
    <image>
      <title>Everything Engineering</title>
      <url>https://abhay.rs/blog/favicon.svg</url>
      <link>https://abhay.rs/blog/favicon.svg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abhay.rs/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bloom filters, the magic of O(1) indexes with rust</title>
      <link>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/backend-intermediate-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/backend-intermediate-0/</guid>
      <description>Bloom filters are probabilistic data-structures, what that means it won’t be right all of the time but most of the time. Why would we use such a thing, cause it BLAZINGLY fast!! We will explore this with Rust cause it’s great and not as hard as you might think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Modular and Extensible Payments System [0]</title>
      <link>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/payments-system-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/payments-system-0/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to structure your payments service with modularity in mind, allowing for easy integration and scalability as your application grows. Learn the art of building an extensible foundation that can adapt to changing business needs, ensuring robustness and agility, to, at the end of the day, maximize profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bouncing Bead - Maths from chaos [0]</title>
      <link>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/maths-from-chaos-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/maths-from-chaos-0/</guid>
      <description>Why Mathematics is truly fascinating, seemingly chaotic behavior once broken down to bits, bytes and variables starts making sense not only helps us to not only predict the future behavior and utilize those predictions to our applications; but the journey of solving a problem provides us with tools for solving the next problem blocking our way.
To put it poetically, the real maths is the tools we made along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub profile visit counter - Backend Basics [0]</title>
      <link>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/visits-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 14:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhay.rs/blog/posts/visits-counter/</guid>
      <description>You might have seen visits counters on some GitHub profiles displaying how many visits a profile has, but do you know how they work, join me as I go in excruciating details on how to make something like that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
